In the spectrum of emotions, I would say joy is up there as top tier.
Contentment is peaceful, happiness is blissful, joy is liberation.
In the joy space, everything feels pleasurable and anything seems possible.
The experience is not meant to be long-lasting, but its impact is long-sustaining.
It reminds us of all that is good and lovely and beautiful.
It lifts us like wind under brightly colored wings and carries us above our sorrows,
lifting us, expanding us, energizing us.
And then like rich oxygen, that's the thick of subsidized feeling charges the crisis in our bodies, our organs, our bones.
It sparks the electrical waves that blow up and down our nervous system.
It infuses each of our trillions of cells with the sheer incredibleness of being alive.
I am of a mind that much of what we need to face our foe is not to be learned, but remembered.
And it is knowledge that they have worked tirelessly for centuries to suppress, but that our cells still possess.
May we all use this portal of possibility that we are existing in to expand our souls' capabilities to connect.
I invite you to head on over to Substack and read the entire essay,
New Moon Musings, Shaking Up the Joy Space.
Get that mood, eh?